I was so much stressed
by my lower back pain.
It was really very severe.
Insurance companies have
their own tantrums, here it was,Tata AIG.
It was a totally bad experience.
The taxi drivers were pouncing on me.
They were like, "Come to me, come to me."
Thank God,
they were not after my luggage.
Anyways, I had to leave
without any treatment.
Tat AIG, I request you
to kindly look into the matter.
I had faced such a situation in Oman,
in the month of December.
Now, again in Europe.
That is, in January 2022.
Mr. Farhan is accompanying me
to a place
from where I can take
a bus or taxi to Muscat.
I am paying 4 Rial to go to Muscat
in this taxi.
ACs have been installed in taxi stands.
I have covered my head with a
handkerchief, means, I am in a gurudwara.
Today was a very bad day for me.
I am so upset.
My day started at about 2 a.m.
I was so much stressed
by my lower back pain.
It was really very severe.
I was in a gurudwara in Ghala.
Waited till morning hoping to feel better.
But it got worse.
At about 6, I was like,
started 'bothering' the people around me.
There was a gentleman in the gurudwara.
I messaged him.
Some people helped me out
and I reached the hospital emergency unit.
I got myself admitted for some time.
And then
I started calling my insurance company.
Inquired whether it would be
covered or not.
Insurance companies have
their own tantrums, here it was, Tata AIG.
It was a totally bad experience.
Why my experience with Tata AIG
turned to be bad,
I had forgotten to mention that
in my previous video recording.
So now, I'm narrating it.
My pain was really very severe
the other night.
First of all, I called
my insurance company to get the details
of their designated
tie-up hospitals in Oman,
where I could avail cashless treatment.
I wanted to undergo a proper treatment
so that my onward journey
to other countries
would be stress-free
and I would be relieved of my pain.
So, my intention was
to get proper treatment.
They were like,
"You can go to any hospital,
and talk to the concerned doctor.
After that, send the bills to us.
We will approve whatever we feel right."
It was very clear from
what they said, that
there were good chances
of non-approval of many of my bills.
We all know how expensive it is
to undergo treatment in a foreign land.
I didn't want to fall prey
to such a situation here.
So, I asked them to provide me the
list of their empaneled hospitals where
I could avail myself the required treatment,
the required diagnosis, and,
they would be
in the form of cashless treatment.
That's the purpose of opting
for a travel insurance.
But, here, it was something else.
And the most important thing,
I was talking
to a third party over the phone.
Tata AIG sold its insurance policy to me.
And now, if you have to discuss anything
regarding claim or such issues,
you have to call this third party.
It was not easy to talk to these people.
Call drops were frequent. I was calling
India from a foreign country.
We all know how expensive these calls are.
And then, calls were getting disconnected.
Conversations could not be completed.
And even when I could speak continuously,
they had their own typical answer,
"We will be able to respond
only when you send us the bills."
The experience at the hospital
turned out to be bad too.
The hospital authorities don't want
to deal with the insurance companies.
They were insisting on getting the
entire money deposited in their hospital.
They were not satisfied with the
guarantee of the insurance companies.
They were like, they have to keep pinging
for money for about 6 months or so.
And so they preferred
to deal with everything in cash.
Travelers like me
buy insurance policies because
God forbid if they land into
such unforeseen circumstances,
they are not forced to lose more money.
But in this hospital, whose name was
NMC or something like that...
It was totally a bad experience.
I met all concerned people,
I met the head of the marketing team.
They were just
shirking off their responsibilities.
They were so casual, they said,
"Our money gets blocked."
"We are not linked to the companies."
I then said, "If that is so,
you can always go for a pre-approval."
"And when they are promising to pay, why
do you refrain from cashless treatment?"
They were like, "They promise but then,
we have to run for 6 months behind them
to get our money."
And so, we prefer cash only.
Anyways, I had to leave
without any treatment.
My lower backache problem
started troubling me again.
Today morning,
I had to go to the hospital in an emergency.
I feel a bit better now.
I was there for 4-5 hours.
I have no interest to continue in Oman.
Let's see what can be done.
Anyways, I had to leave
without any treatment.
Right now, I have taken some painkillers.
This is the hospital,
right in front of me.
The area is Ruwi.
And why did I come here?
I wanted to end my trip here.
I am headed to the UAE to proceed further.
I had planned to visit Europe
after my Oman trip.
Flights had already been booked.
I had to fly from Dubai by Emirates.
Emirates had already informed me, that,
before boarding, I need to produce
the RTPCR test report.
Without that
you are not allowed to board the flight.
But here, a different kind of problem
was waiting for me.
This is the
Badr Al Samaa Hospital of Ruwi.
I had already arrived there
to take my RTPCR test.
I was about to take the RTPCR test when
I came to know that Emirates
accepts only those reports that have been
tested in labs at Dubai.
They accept the results
from those labs alone.
The only way out was to reach Dubai,
as soon as possible.
Take the test there
and then board my flight.
Less than 36 hours are left
for my flight to depart from Dubai.
Now finally, from Ruwi, I'm going
to a place called Rusayl,
from where I can get the long route buses.
From Rusayl,
I will board a shared taxi to Sohar.
A very good friend of Mr. Farhat.
will help me out
to reach the border from Sohar.
Mr. Farhat and his friend Mr. Gulam
are none less than angels to me.
Mr. Gulam is
a very good friend of Mr. Farhat.
And so, he has happily agreed
to drop me at the border in his car.
The way ahead,
that is the border between the two
has to be worked out by me.
From there, I will be accompanied
by my good friend Mr. Taranjeet.
From Dubai to the border,
is a two-hour-long journey.
The distances are all so complicated.
I tried my level best
not to trouble people.
I didn't want to bother them a lot.
I am planning my way out
to create the least disturbances.
But I am really grateful to all those
who stand by me to help me out.
I also wanted to share the changing rules
due to the Covid pandemic.
I was almost done
with the RTPCR test here.
The bus ticket was in my hand
and I had to cancel it.
That report will not be accepted
and so I backed out from this place.
Now, I have to take the test in Dubai.
I do agree that the RTPCR test should be
mandatory and it's a necessity too.
It is equally important to protect
Ourselves and protect our nation.
It's good to know
if we are infected or not.
But, things are being made
more and more complex.
I am so exhausted.
I have a terrible headache.
Since morning, I am running here and there
without any proper food.
The time right now is 6.30 p.m.
I am sitting in a taxi.
I am on the outskirts of Muscat.
I am headed to Sohar.
It's a 2-hour journey from here.
The fare is 4 Rial.
Generally, it's about 5 Rial or so.
You can negotiate to 4 Rials.
But I had a terrible experience
at the taxi stand.
The taxi drivers were pouncing on me.
They were like, "Come to me, come to me."
Thank God, they were not after my luggage.
I am feeling somewhat hungry.
I had nothing good since morning.
The pain has started troubling me again.
I'll take some food
and then some medicine.
Maybe, I'll feel better.
It's 9 p.m. I'm a little ahead of Sohar.
The reason for the halt was - food.
Probably,
this is my last Indian meal in Oman.
Yeah, I said probably because,
I have yet to cross the border.
I went to wash my hands and my face
and noticed the redness of my eyes.
I am so exhausted.
The whole journey was so tiring.
But, the taste of Indian food
made me feel fresh again.
I feel better.
So, I have arrived at Sohar.
The taxi dropped me
at the crossing near Lulu.
Lulu is the hypermarket
about which I was talking.
They have quite a big chain here
and perhaps in the Gulf too.
And there, I met Mr. Gulam.
He is here, right in front of me.
-Thanks a lot.
-Hi.
Thank you very much
for bringing me here.
I have also thanked that gentleman,
because today...
Yes, Please?
-You belong to which place?
-I'm from Gujarat.
Oh! You are from Gujarat.
-Which place in Gujarat?
-Porbandar.
-Porbandar? Did you come here long back?
-What?
You are staying here for many years?
I came in 2003...
I have my nephew here
and he called me back.
The other gentleman opened the door
and quickly entered the video frame.
I wanted to thank you 'on the camera'.
I'm really grateful that you're driving me
to the border, it's almost 9 p.m now.
Thank you so much and thanks to Mr. Farhat
for making this meet.
It feels good
to meet the Indian community in Oman.
Today, it's 9th January 2022.
I always upload my videos on Sundays.
But, this Sunday, I couldn't.
There are two reasons.
Firstly, I am journeying.
It was a long journey.
I have to board three flights.
But now, that has again been extended,
as one flight stands canceled.
Now, in such cases, the travel insurance
again comes to the picture.
In case of any cancellations,
or any such unexpected issues,
the travel insurance covers the risk.
My insurance company, Tata AIG
was also covering this insurance.
But again, the same issue.
I wanted to share this experience as well,
so I am shooting this in this video.
Two days before I started this journey,
I received a mail informing me that
my second flight, the middle one...
I had booked 3 different PNRs
in 3 different airlines.
I had made direct bookings from airlines,
and not booked through any agencies.
Please do take care of this thing, I had
shared this information in another video.
The flights are quite uncertain these days
because of Covid.
Some are canceled, some re-scheduled.
some are delayed as well.
Rules keep on changing now and then.
This creates lots of problems for people.
So, if you book through a third party,
like Yatra, Make my Trip, etc,
then what happens is,
airlines make their own deductions,
and these agencies go a step further.
If booked directly, at least,
that (3rd Party share) money would be saved.
Nowadays... I have mentioned this
in my earlier videos also,
that these third parties
create a lot of other issues.
These are also known as OTAs.
They trouble you a lot.
To avoid being harassed by them,
to avoid a lot of other issues...
Since March 2020 or say,
since the onset of Covid,
I always book my tickets
directly from the airline websites.
This time also, I did the same.
There were three different PNRs, but,
my middle flight got canceled.
They informed me in the mail
that they would re-schedule
and make a fresh ticket
and I need not do anything.
The re-scheduled flight deferred
from the previous one by 6-7 hours.
Because of this new re-scheduled flight,
the last flight of my journey,
was going to get missed.
I called my travel insurance,
and the same scene again.
It was again the third party.
I wanted to explain that
I received a mail
two days prior to my departure,
about re-schedule of my second flight
and that ultimately
the third flight was going to be missed.
And if I cancel the third one, the new
ticket was going to be more expensive.
I wanted to ask, whether I should
book the flight now itself,
or wait for some more time.
That's because re-scheduling
is so common these days.
I was coming from Europe,
and because of the rise in Covid cases,
I am facing a lot of issues.
Flights are being re-scheduled frequently.
Rules and regulations keep on changing.
Airports get crowded all of a sudden,
because of sudden changes in the rules.
So, I also said that,
if I buy the ticket,
and if there's any change again,
because 3 flights are involved here,
so, should I wait for the second flight
to reach its destination.
And after I reach the second destination,
I can book the third one at the airport,
though it would cost me more.
But I will be benefited,
like if there's any further change...
Before taking any further steps,
I wanted to share this
with my insurance company
and act according to the advice
given by the company.
"Send the documents, we'll look further."
This was their stereotype reply.
The same issue again.
The call dropped a number of times.
Calls got disconnected a lot of times.
Tata AIG, I request you
to kindly look into the matter.
I faced this issue
in the first week of December, in Oman.
And again in Europe.
And this is January 2022.
The situation is the same.
There are absolutely no changes.
I have shared my experience with Tata AIG,
and have put all the facts
in a transparent manner.
But, Please... Because I would
need travel insurance in the near future,
even you may need the same.
Please feel free to share your travel
experience with other companies,
if you have claimed at any point in time.
Please, do share the same.
There's a Facebook group
of tourist helpline where you can share.
You can even share
in the comments section.
That would help other people too.